JORDAN MAX

github/jordmax12 | https://jdmdev-portfolio.herokuapp.com/ | jordmax12@gmail.com

SUMMARY

Fullstack polyglot developer with a proven record of solutioning unusual problems with innovative technologies. With six years of experience in a multitude of engineering disciplines such as: **DevOps**, **Backend**, **Database**, **Frontend**, and **Mobile** development. Can **adapt to any change** needed to solve a problem, doesn't mind **learning new things** along the way.

EXPERIENCE

Software Engineer

July 2019 to present Chicago, IL

Syngenta

- Helped facilitate the development and maintenance of **AWS Codebuild** and **CircleCI** pipelines, using the **Serverless Framework** and cloudformation templates for **infrastructure** as **code**.
- Built a plethora of microservices using **AWS Lambda** functions, **api gateways** and built seamless **external data integrations** (salesforce, and other in house API's) utilizing **SQS/SNS** with lambda triggers via **publisher/subscriber design pattern**. These **microservices** were built in a modular fashion and allow for multiple applications to be using them, opposed to API's being tailored for one application, by utilizing **OpenAPI** and **schema validation on destructive** (create, update, delete) API calls for both incoming requests and outgoing responses.
- Primary focusing on building re-usable API's, packages and SDK's using nodejs (on occassion python and other languages for fun). Built a front-end private npm package to facilitate as a UI-kit for our front-end teams to build and maintain re-usable react components, authentication system using AWS Cognito and a number of federated identities for SSO, notification system using Twilio and AWS SES, and helped develop normalized database drivers for technologies such as: Neo4J, DynamoDB, and MySQL.
- One of the main **DevOps support lines** for our entire dev team of 20+ engineers (locally), and helping mentor our junior developers/interns so they can grow and become rockstar developers through **pair programming, PR's and "lunch and learns"**.
- Lightly used technologies: AWS Lambda, AWS DynamoDB, AWS RDS, AWS EC2, AWS CodeBuild, NodeJS, Serverless Framework, ReactJS... and more.

Software Developer

July 2017 — July 2019 Chicago, IL

FCB Chicago

- Tasked with **learning new technologies to find innovative solutions** to meet the needs of **demanding clientele**.
- Majority of work done in Linux, Express, Mongo/MySQL, Javascript stack.
- Created and maintains a flagship product being built using AI. Securely building the back-end encompassing a secure exposed API, third party API integration mini-services, admin portal and more.
- Interacts and negotiates with project managers, design, UX and tech leads; communicates how code changes may impact future releases and overall architecture.
- Regularly works well with **new or unknown programming languages (or frameworks)** while excelling at adapting quickly to the differences in syntax within tight deadlines.

Mostly used technologies: GraphQL, NodeJS/Express, ES6 Javascript, ReactJS, KeystoneJS,
Docker, AWS (ECS, EC2 Load Balancers, Route53, CodePipeline/CodeBuild, SES/SNS/SQS,
CodeCommit, IAM, S3 and more), Alexa

Full Stack & Mobile Developer

June 2016 — June 2017 Chicago, IL

Newser

- Singularly lead mobile development for new iOS and Android apps using a mostly shared codebase
- Updated existing code while optimizing deficiencies and improved performance by 50%
- Generated revenue by implementing Facebook Ad Network and RevMob into the app which resulted in \$20K annual revenue increase
- → *Technologies used*: ASP.NET 4.6, MSQL, Web Forms, Xamarin Forms/iOS, Azure, TFS, jQuery, HTML5, CSS3, SQL Management Studio

Full Stack & Mobile Developer

Feb 2015 — May 2016

NextCrew

Glenview, IL

- Designed, developed and deployed hybrid iOS/Android app using the Cordova framework
- → Lead a .NET project which communicated with **Quickbooks Online** endpoints to streamline our clients accounting needs
- → *Technologies used*: ASP.NET, Web Forms, Cordova, MSQL, TFS, RactiveJS, Semantic UI, Bootstrap, JIRA, Xcode 9

EDUCATION

Columbia College Chicago

May, 2015

BA, Mobile and Software Programming

3.5 GPA | Dean's List recipient

- → Studied data structures, database design, mobile programming and web application development.
- → Completed various projects such as: Sweets Complete (in both: PHP & ASP.NET MVC 5 using Entity Frameworks), Spark Help (ASP.NET MVC5 using Entity Frameworks), Hamstar (Unity3D, C#, Javascript), Procedural AI pathfinding node generation algorithm (C#)